I've got major news for the medical
applications of the tiny human brains
you can grow in a jar if you want to.
For people who are new here, yes, those
are tiny human brains. They are just
disembodied. Are those eyes? Yes. Do
they work? Kind of. They're essentially
the same ocular cups that you would have
while you were developing. You can use
them to run computation on. There's even
companies that sell out a subscription
to use these little guys. First off,
these guys have been used in both mice
and monkey models to heal induced
strokes. That would mean that you have
something like a primate. A part of
their brain has been purposefully
damaged and brain organoids are grown
and then brought in and allowed to
proliferate. They actually do just fine.
This would be the first real treatment
for strokes that has really ever been
conducted. There have been a lot of
research trying to use stem cells. It's
not that effective. Turns out if you
grow a tiny organoid, so a immature
human organ that resembles a fetal brain
very closely, it does a lot better at
healing damaged areas. Interestingly, a
lot of this research has shown that the
older brain organoids are the ones that
do better. That's a little bit
counterintuitive because these little
guys can't be kept alive all that long.
When they were first developed, you
could keep them alive for about a month
or then 3 months. And now you can keep
them alive for about a year. Turns out
it is pretty hard to grow a human brain
without, you know, a body. I don't know
what my hair is doing today. Now, if
you're familiar with Parkinson's, it's a
disorder in which the brain stops
producing dopamine effectively. It is
progressive and it is not great to have.
There is some question if it's
autoimmune. There can be genetic
components and it can strike randomly.
Incidentally, if you have ADHD, you are
at risk. Which means I'm I'm I'm
screwed. I accept it. There's also, you
know, the family history issue. You can
grow human brain organoids. You can
transplant them into the skull of a rat
and they differentiate into correct
tissue types that are actually capable
of producing dopamine and reversing the
movement disorder. Now you might be
asking are there any ethical concerns
because you are taking human brain
tissue and putting it into a mouse. It
does change their behavior. We do know
that. I haven't seen any studies
specifically addressing whether or not
they might make mice more intelligent.
If you just had an induced stroke and a
you know a brain organoid come in, even
if it is human, you still had a lot of
damage. That'd be pretty hard to think
that that could happen. But we do know
that if you take a embryionic mouse and
fit human neural stem cells in it, they
are smarter. I have seen a lot of
arguments from both sides for the human
brain organoids. Is it ethical to use
them in chimeas? Is it ethical to use
them for computation? I think there's a
better argument for computation not
being ethical. Not even a whole lot of
evidence that they're that good at it.
Our brains are just not that good at
running calculations. But the use of
these little guys for medicine has a lot
of applications. Obviously, when you are
doing research, one of the big things to
consider is the potential suffering of
an animal going to result in significant
scientific or medical advancement. Aside
from, you know, being able to be put
into a brain, you can also put them and
attach them to muscle tissue and they
can control the muscle tissue. They're
very powerful new pieces of technology.
This is really exciting. And you might
be asking, why hasn't this been moved to
humans yet? It seems like they can
provide a treatments for a variety of
conditions like strokes, Parkinson's,
probably more. When our brains fail to
function, we can just grow a little
fetal brain and then transplant it into
our skulls. It worked in monkeys. It
worked in mice. Why not us? It is
complicated. I think it is rapidly
progressing towards human trials, and
I'm excited when we get there. But our
brains are kind of a precious thing. And
if you try a radical experimental
treatment and it doesn't go well, that
could be worse than the actual
condition. So be patient. We will get
there. It does look really promising.